We'll beat anybody in the world, and I
think we're going to win next Sunday.
>> [screaming]
>> Can't wait.
Hey G, what's this past week been like
for you because you guys are hard at it
as far as scouting the college prospects
before the NFL draft, and now you're
here in Phoenix at the annual league
meetings.
>> Yeah, well, it's it's always good to
to get a chance to be around these other
head coaches, have conversation with
those guys.
Really get a chance to get the nuances
of the league and some of the things
that we're trying to improve on as a
league and
just over education, you know, for all
of us, you know, so
it's it's been good.
It's still a process to to to get
through everything, get through all the
meetings, but to get a chance to be
around these owners, get a chance to be
around these other head coaches, it's
been a good experience.
>> Where do you think the league is going?
I'll tell you what, when you when you
look at the things when it
when you talk about AI, I mean, those
are some very very intriguing things
that we're actually moving towards. So,
listen, it's something that that we can
take advantage of as a coaching staff,
and we're looking at every option to be
able to do that. And listen, we have
some of these young innovative guys on
our coaching staff that have a good idea
of how to educate all of us, you know,
when it comes to that, and we're going
to utilize that as much as we can.
>> That's one thing you emphasized in
Indianapolis. You really like the blend
of the coaching staff that you have some
seasoned veterans like yourself, and
then you do have some younger guys.
>> Yeah, and again, that was intentional.
And everything about what we're doing
and what we're going to do is is going
to be process oriented. And I really
took some time to really dig deeper into
what that means, and
a lot of times you have this vision of
of where you want to go, all right? But
being process oriented means you're very
detailed on the steps that you're going
to take to be able to get to that
vision. And that's with the coaching
staff, that's with building our team,
that's with basically anything that
we're doing. You know, we want to be a
process and don't miss miss many steps.
And I think sometimes people think that
you elongate a lot of things that you're
doing, but you're really that's just
trying to make sure you hit all those
steps.
You spoke about options before.
When you guys approach this off season,
you look at the global landscape of the
quarterback position,
why do you end up with Geno, and what do
you think about him coming back to the
green and white for second time? Yeah,
that was a um
um something that me, Mo Woods, and
everybody that was involved
wanted to make sure we took our time.
It's like, what guy actually fits the
Jets? And when you look at Geno, he's a
guy that has a chip on the shoulder.
He's a guy that's highly competitive.
He's a guy that that really really loves
football.
He's a guy He's a guy that has learned
from some of his mistakes as a young
player and now want to make sure that he
understands that, man, he's a key
key component of that locker room and
getting everybody on the same page. So,
when you look at those things, those
things are some of the cultural
things that we want to have on this
team. And man, there's nothing better
than having a guy with a chip on the
shoulder ready to go out there and play.
So, I look forward to him coming out,
being there for the first day of our
phase one, working out with the players,
getting a chance to get cohesive with
all the players,
and understanding exactly what we're
trying to do on offense. Do you like
that setup with him, Frank Reich, you
signed Bill Musgrave to head your
quarterbacks? As far as that room is
concerned, then overall offensively, you
bring back four of your top five
offensive line starters. You signed
Dalton Parham in free agency. You got
all your backs back. We know you put the
tag on Breece Hall. Yes.
And Garrett Wilson
leading your receivers, but like AD
Mitchell is another year, you know, with
those guys. So, I mean, you just hit it
like really like on the head when it
comes to our offense.
Everything with us always starts in the
trenches. That's O-line and D-line. And
to be able to have four of the five
starters back, be able to pick up a guy
like Parham, and then put Geno behind
something like that along with Frank
Musgrave, and let's not to mention Seth
Seth and Ryan. He's another guy, young
guy. Um very innovative that's going to
come with some really good ideas. So,
I'm excited about what we have on
offense, and not to mention that we're
going to continue to build upon that.
It's exciting for us. Do you think Geno
can help unlock some things down the
field because if you look at him
throughout his career, he's made
defensive coordinators
like yourself back in the day, and
you'll be calling plays this year.
Defend every blade of grass. Well,
>> [clears throat]
>> I just remember my time defending him,
and you guys can go back and look at,
you know, how those games went playing
him.
And they were tough, and he has an
electric arm.
He's extremely smart, and the thing that
I told him that I just I clearly saw
from playing against him is just how
he's matured over his years and being
able to just take command of the offense
when it comes to protections, when it
comes to getting in and out of plays,
and putting us in the right play. All
right, I think that's going to be a huge
thing that Frank's going to be able to
take advantage of, a guy that has seen
it before, that knows how to get the
offense in the right play, and we want
to take advantage of that as much as
possible.
>> Have you thought about what the
play-action game could look like?
Because we're talking about you want to
build in the trenches.
>> Yeah. You look Frank look at Frank's
history. Whenever he's been calling
plays, that's Hey, that is an emphasis,
and you we know what you want to do. You
want to run the football. Yeah, well,
that has a lot to do with the guys that
we have, too. We have an O-line that's
aggressive,
and they take great pride in the run
game. And then you look at the backs
that we have.
Obviously, Breece is a is a is a top
back, and he's going to do outstanding
in this offense. Then you have BA, then
you have Isaiah. So, I think we have a
chance to run the ball really well. When
you have a chance to run it well, that
opens up your play-action game. So,
Garrett, AD,
Mason, all those guys, skill guys that
we have, man, it's just going to open
them up a lot more. What about the
defensive side of the ball? Did you go
into this thing thinking that I need a
couple quarterbacks on that side as well
because I've been saying that you guys
got three quarterbacks this off season.
One is Geno on the offensive side. Two
is Demario, and the third one back there
in the secondary is Quincy Williams.
>> Yeah, well, you know what? That was a
plan from the very beginning, not just
on the defensive side, but just on the
whole team
of trying to um
trying to get an influx of these veteran
guys
to be a part of what we're building. I
think we had the second youngest team in
the league last year.
And listen, those guys are bought in.
When I say they're they're all bought
in, so now we get some of these veteran
guys that's been there, done that, know
how to do it, and can try to keep us
sustainable, you know, from what we're
doing. And that's what those guys have
done, you know, so when it comes to the
defense in particular, man, we have some
salty guys. And I mean, that's how you
want to play defense. Um but I love
everything about what we're doing. And
again, we're going to continue to try to
build.
Did you go in the off season saying,
"Hey, we got to get bigger on that side
of the ball"? Um
because I see some
trademarks when you look at Parcells
back in the day and and the way he ran
the thing. Yeah. Physical, no doubt
about it. You want every defense to be
physical. I know that. But but just when
you look at the size dimension now.
Well, it's a
it's a big man's game. I think we all
know that.
>> [snorts]
>> Um
and more or less, just how we want to
play defense, the things that we want to
do.
I think all those things take part in
the type of players that you want to
make sure you put on your team. Sweat is
a guy that can control the middle, and
and we wanted that. If you look at what
he's done over over the time he's been
in the league, he's been pretty good at
run defense, and he's been sneaky when
it comes to being able to push the
pocket, you know, as a pass rusher. But
all the other guys, David Onyemata, who
I know very well, I mean, not only is he
a good run defender, but he is a sneaky
good pass rusher, also.
And that just goes to everybody you
know, that we brought in. Kingsley
Enagbare, obviously Demario, the things
that they can do defensively actually
fit what we're trying to do
schematically. So, that's that's always
a plus when you can get the guys that
fit what you're trying to do
schematically. Schematically, do you
have more options now because you
mentioned like Sweat before. I know
people are saying, "Well, he wants to
run a 3-4." And I say, "Well, he can run
a 3-4, but you know, that's a number of
plays per game because you're going to
be changing this up." Yeah, I think it's
funny when you hear that.
Listen, we're going to be whatever we
have to be to be successful. And the
thing is, I think in this day and age um
you know, you could say 3-4, you could
say 4-3. I mean, listen, it's you know,
teams are so multiple nowadays that
meant to be able to jump in and out of
different fronts means is always
advantageous you know, to a defense
because you don't want to just sit in
one spot and let the offense know
exactly where guys are going to be.
What's your selling point with guys
because to a man, you talked to Demario.
Obviously played with you before. He
knows what you're all about, but he
wanted to come here.
Mecca said he jumps on the phone with
you, and there's an instant connection
there. So, when you tell guys, "Hey,
man, I want you to join this crew."
I mean,
why do you have the instant buy-in? Um
well, it's it's [clears throat] it's a
lot more than than that.
Um
I think players know that I don't BS
them. And um I know exactly, you know,
where we are, and I know exactly that we
didn't have the year that we wanted to
have. Um
and when you explain that to them and
and don't try to sell them on anything,
but just give them, "Listen, this is the
vision. This is where we're trying to
go.
All right? And this is where I know we
can go with you being a part of that.
>> [snorts]
>> Um this is how we go about practice.
This is what I believe in. These are the
type of players that that we want. We
want guys that really love football. How
much do you really love it? Yeah. You
know, and I think I get passionate when
I get a chance to talk about that. And I
think they feel that. And I think um a
lot of times when you authentic about
how you want to do things, when you are
authentic about who you are as a coach,
I think a lot of times that resonates
with players really, really well and
they want to be a part of that. How much
does it help you not only on the field,
but off the field, inside the locker
room, in the meeting room, when you got
guys like Onyemata, Yeah.
>> DeMario, Yeah.
>> and and Minkah. Well, those um I will I
will say those guys real quick cuz those
guys been with me and they know exactly
what I'm about, you know? And when you
have guys, when you bring another guy
like Minkah, who um just his history of
what he's done in this league speaks for
itself. Um and now the young guys have
someone to point to and say, "Man, this
is what I want to be like and this is
how I want to do it." Okay, you have no
excuse now. So, all you got to do is
just jump in with them, you know, cuz I
know what those guys are going to do.
So, now they got to bring those other
guys. And those guys have have a
responsibility, too. And they know that.
And and I've stressed it with those
guys. And I think they they understand
they like that part of it. Um it's not
just about you, it's about bringing
everybody else along with you. And those
young guys have to buy into that. Not
too far away from the draft. We got to
let you get out of here, but can you
speak about the options you guys have as
far as the draft capital is concerned?
And you went on the ground, like we
mentioned at the top. You've been all
over the place. Yeah. Cross-country
tour. What is What's it been like?
>> listen, um I love every part of it. Um I
mean, Moosh has done an outstanding job,
him and his staff, as far as uh setting
the table of these are some guys, here's
the information behind these guys. Now,
let's take a look and see which one fits
us best. And to have two first-round
picks, to have two second-round picks,
to mean to have the picks that we have
at the middle and at towards the end of
the draft, that really sets your team.
That really sets your team. That
first-round picks, that those are the
easy ones. It's the ones from the third,
fourth, fifth, or sixth round, those are
the ones that really set your team up
for success. And with our coaches having
to develop those guys, so I'm excited
about it. Um I love having those later
picks, also, cuz it gives you a chance
to um truly pick some guys that they
might not have all the traits that you
have, but they have something in them
that you know that you can develop to
make them a key part of your team. So,
I'm I'm excited about that part. Great
seeing you as always. Appreciate your
time. No doubt. Appreciate you.
Darren, this is a bit of a homecoming
for you, right? You grew up down the
street. It is. Just grew up about 12
minutes up the street, so it feels good
to be back. I love the heat. I miss the
heat. Um
got in Saturday night, got a chance to
stop by my mom's house, see my mom and
some family, so that was nice. How is
she doing? She's doing great. She's
doing great. But I have a brother and
sister here still in town, didn't get to
see them, but I got got a chance to see
my mom and
feels good to be back. I've asked you
this before, but you were a star high
school quarterback. So, do you remember
those days?
>> Oh, yeah, I remember those days. Those
are the It feels like a lifetime ago,
but I do remember those days.
Those were good days. Um
well-traveled of late, right? Yeah.
>> You were all over the place,
cross-country, last week. We were last
week. It was great to get out. We we
started down in Miami, were there, and
then we jumped up, Notre Dame pro day,
went over to Ohio State, went over to
Texas Tech, and then finished at
Alabama, working out Ty Simpson. It was
a great week. Um Good up
>> opportunity for me to get out there and
get some exposure to these some of these
players I hadn't seen, see them up close
and personal, work out, get to spend
some time with them, have some dinner,
get to know them a little more on a
personal level, um which was great. And
also,
you know, just traveling that whole week
with AG, Frank, Billy Musgrave came with
us because we got some exposure to some
quarterbacks, and just being around them
for the week is so so productive on some
level, just having football
conversations all the time and about the
team, so it was great. It was It was a
It was a long week, but it flew by. And
now we're here, and I flew here Saturday
and
excited to get back to Jersey at the end
of this week and jump right into the
draft process. Uh do you really like
that room now when you're talking about
Reich and all the experiences he has?
And speaking of experience, Bill
Musgrave. And then we're going to get to
the quarterback position. You added a
veteran there in Geno Smith. Yeah. I do.
I like the room. And just on on the
Frank and Billy piece, like I said, it's
been great talking quarterback play with
them and offensive play this past week.
And Frank's really in
He's into the draft process. I mean,
he's texting me all the time. He He's
been great just getting to know those
guys. And yeah, like you mentioned, we
have Geno in the room, an experienced
player who's been through a lot in this
league, played at a high level, can
still throw the heck out of the ball,
can make all the throws, tough. So,
really excited to get Geno back, see him
um
kind of get on the field in these OTAs
and lead the team. What are those
conversations like when you're talking
with Frank and Bill because you all
three played the position? Yeah, it No,
they're great. They're awesome cuz we
all kind of have perspectives and
different experiences and talk about it.
So, they're a lot of fun. Obviously,
AG's in that, too, and he sees it
through a different lens. And they're
they're fun conversations. We can go
around and round. Why was Geno the right
fit for you guys right now? He was, you
know, just just his experiences
and what was available and him being
able He can still make all throws.
Always had a great arm, you know? And
and we we were able to have some
conversations with him. Obviously, the
Raiders granted us permission, had some
good conversations with Geno. It felt
like it was a really good fit for for
all parties. So, excited to get him
back. Uh what do you make of his past 4
years? Obviously, things didn't work out
with the Raiders last year, overall. But
that 3-year one 3-year run with Seattle.
Uh why did he have a
a career resurgence? Yeah, exactly. He
He played really good ball, you know,
those those years in Seattle. And then
obviously last year had a little bit of
a down year. And there's a lot of things
that go into that, you know? But we feel
really good about where he's at
physically and excited to get get to
work with him, put some pieces around
him, and help him out. Yeah, one thing I
was asking AG about was
do you like that, hey, we have the
ability to be two-dimensional on offense
now? When you're looking at Geno's
numbers, I mean, one thing that he's
always done is got a high
completion accuracy. And those 4 years,
you average them,
he's nearly 3,800 yards per year. I know
he's talked publicly about the fact that
he wants to get the turnovers down, as
well. Yeah. Yeah, and that's that's a
group effort, you know? That's that's a
collaborative effort that we that we got
to, you know, be on the same page with
the with the players and make sure he's
protected up. It all starts really up
front. Make sure he's protected up
front, you got a good run game, you can
build it all off that, and and be
multi-dimensional, like you said.
Offensively, you added a piece up front
in Dalton Parham. What did you like
about Dalton?
Dalton was, you know, obviously with the
departure of of Simpson, we had a hole
there at left guard. Dalton was a guy we
targeted and and had our eye on. A guy
that's young, has played a lot of
football. He's played left guard, he's
played center, he's played right guard.
So, he's got versatility, smart. I feel
really good about adding him to the
group, you know, a group where four of
the five are returning. And we brought
back Max Mitchell. We brought back
Chuks. We brought back Xavier Newman.
So, keeping continuity in that room,
we we believe will help the room. And
Steve Heiden's coming back. And I look
forward to watching that group take the
next step and continue to get better. We
can lean on that group. We're going to
see what happens over the next few
weeks, but you talked about a little bit
before that you like the receiver
position with Garrett leading the way.
Yeah. Getting Garrett back healthy this
year will obviously be huge. And we'll
we'll make the focal point Garrett there
in the receiver room. But I'm I'm I'm
excited to see AD Mitchell take the next
step, Isaiah Williams, uh Aryan, those
guys continue to grow and develop and
take the next step. But no different
than any position on the field. We'll
always look, you know, at the wide
receiver market, whether it's via trade,
on the street, the draft, and want to
add guys that we think they can help or
improve our depth. What about the
defensive outlook as you enter the
off-season? When you and AG got
together,
what was the plan? How did you want to
attack this thing? Well, generally
speaking, going into the off-season, you
know, we looked at the roster. We had
one of the younger rosters in the NFL.
So, we we we we were going to have an
emphasis. We wanted to inject some
veteran experience and leadership onto
the team as a whole. And then on
defense, finding certain pieces that
were going to fit the hole as well and
add some some experienced players like
David Onyemata up front, Double D at
linebacker, Minkah Fitzpatrick in the in
the secondary. Then two edge players,
you know, with Efe Obada and Ossai. You
know,
feel really good about those pieces we
added and excited about those see those
guys playing this defense. What do you
think DeMario and Minkah, and you
mentioned DO, as well.
What can they add to the culture here?
Just that. They can bring
um
that veteran leadership, you know, that
experience, help build the culture, the
toughness, the grittiness, the
professionalism, all those things, cuz
that's what they've been their whole
careers and have displayed that. So,
excited to see that. So, now looking
ahead,
you got number two overall, 16 in the
first round. You got that
top pick in round two. You got four
picks in the top 44.
What happens now at this point when you
get back to Jersey as far as the draft
board is concerned?
>> Yeah, excited about those opportunities
ahead of us. And you know, what happens
now is we get back later in the week,
and I'll have meetings starting
Thursday, Friday, and then all the
scouts come in Sunday, and then that
Monday we'll pick it up, and we'll be in
draft meetings for the, you know, 2 3
weeks leading up to the draft, have the
coaches in there, very collaborative,
detailed, thorough process as we build
the board. And and I'm looking forward
to it. It's a time of year I I I really
enjoy. I love it. So, I I look forward
to it. Uh
your philosophy on trading overall.
You've made a number major deals here,
including
in this off-season, Germaine Johnson
sent to the Titans and bringing in
Davondre Sweat back. Yeah, just in terms
of trade. That's just another mechanism
to build the the team and the roster.
Um,
but in terms of Germaine, just
we were forecasting kind of the the edge
market in free agency in the draft and
felt like we could add some pieces
there. He was in the last year of the
fifth year.
Um, it's hard to find DTs. Davondre was
a piece and a and a type we were really
looking to add. So, glad it worked out
for all parties there. Um, but yeah, I'm
always going to pick up the phone,
always going to be making calls and it
just exhausting all options and
mechanisms, you know,
Anyway, player acquisition.
Does that include number two overall?
Because I mean, that is a valuable pick
and then everybody after, you know this
better than
everyone that
after night one of the draft, that 33rd
overall selection, everybody's looking
at their board and saying, "Who's
remaining?" It can be. [clears throat]
It can be. And those are discussions I'm
looking forward to having this this next
month as we build the board and talk
about strategically, you know, the pick
two, the 16, the 33 and how that might
unfold. You never really know until you
get in to the draft, but it fun to build
those boards and have those projections
and talk about the different scenarios.
Daren, always appreciate your time.